Guide to the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, 1936-1939
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 4: Microfiche, 1936-1939; (10 boxes)
  - Circus 216, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Mrs. Ted Sandwina, Performer 212th Armory (Roberts)".
  - Circus 235, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children's audience Armory (Waterbury)".
  - Circus 245, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Christmas Carnival Mecca temple (Black Haber, Helkin)".
  - Circus 287, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers".
  - Circus 295, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Heckscher Foundation Star Casino (Monoson)".
  - Circus 311, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers New Star Casino (Wernli)".
  - Circus 338, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children's audience; Ridgwood Grove (Monoson)".
  - Circus 441, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Elmhurst, Long Island (Arnold).
  - Circus 462, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Astoria, Long Island (Wernli)".
  - Circus 478, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers; African warriors Soundview Baseball Field".
  - Circus 529, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers; personnel Adelphi Theatre (Wernli)".
  - Circus 538, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience New Rochelle (Waterbury)".
  - Circus 595, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers; audience Stauch's Coney Island (Wernli)".
  - Circus 614, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 96)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers; audience E. Orange, New jersey (Wernli)".
  - Circus 622, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Wagons (Nielsen)".
  - Circus 650, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Poster (Nielsen)".
  - Circus 687, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Circus 692, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Band; backstage; audience; personnel; Hollis Long Island (Rose, Wernli)".
  - Circus 699, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers; personnel Sunnyside, Long Island (Waterbury)".
  - Circus 730, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writings on their envelopes, it reads "Performers, wild west Astoria, Long Island (Helkin)".
  - Circus 762, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Circus 806, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Publicity".
  - Circus 807, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume portraits; June Lancaster, Edna Martell, Peter White Cloud".
  - Circus 813, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Indian costume".
  - Circus 848, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers New Rochelle".
  - Circus 889, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Armory".
  - Circus 917, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Wild west; clowns; performer".
  - Circus No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performers; tents; audience, Sunnyside, Long Island".
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) 316, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Winners (Helkin)".
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) 324, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Winners (Wernli)".
  - Clap Hands 14, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Baudeville".
  - Class of '29 5, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Backstage".
  - Class of '29 92, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; cast portraits".
  - Class of '29 513, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shot; Council House (Wernli)".
  - The Clock on the Stairs 305, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Daly's Theatre (Black, Wernli)".
  - The Comedy of Errors 15, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production Shots".
  - Community Drama 73, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dancer; production Rutgers Church House".
  - Community Drama 82, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "University Settlement House".
  - Community Drama 160, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Advent Episcopal Church".
  - Community Drama 209, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "The Gingham Girl Bronx Wintergarden (Haber)".
  - Community Drama 279, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Public School #187 (Helkin)".
  - Community Drama 347, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Southern play Public School #21 Woodside Long Island (Black)".
  - Community Drama 373, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Pageant Bronx Wintergarden (Wernli)".
  - Community Drama 435, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "YMHA (Wernli)".
  - Community Drama 448, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Hebrew Orphan Asylum (Waterbury)".
  - Community Drama 705, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Riverdale Presbyterian Church; (Horn)".
  - Community Drama 706, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads :YWCA Harlem (Horn)".
  - Community Drama 709, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Provincetown Theatre (Steiner)".
  - Community Drama 714, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Provincetown Theatre (Wernli)".
  - Community Drama 926, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Erza Stone with Gudson Guild Children Mansfield Theatre".
  - Community Drama 941, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Drama contest University Settlement House".
  - Community Drama 949, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Contest Provincetown Theatre".
  - The Conjur' Man Dies 16, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan".
  - The Conjur' Man Dies 77, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marquee Lefayette Theatre".
  - The Conjur' Man Dies 144, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Consolation 354, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Riverdale Presbyterian Church; (Arnold)".
  - Consulation 399, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Rutgers Church House (Monoson)".
  - Consulation 436, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cropsey Avenue Methodist Church; (Monoson)".
  - Constitutional Pageant 493, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Special event Madison Square Garden (Wernli)".
  - Coriolanus 642, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portrait of Shakespeare".
  - Coriolanus 655, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots (Wernli)".
  - Coriolanus 710, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience Manual Training High School Annex; (Horn)".
  - Coriolanus 739, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "(Nielsen)"
  - The Cradle will Rock 366, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative has writing on it's envelope that reads "Rehearsal shots (Black)" and one positive has writing on it's envelope that reads "Rehearsal shots Maxine Elliott's Theatre (Helkin)".
  - Cradle will Rock 370, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    1 negative and 2 positives. One positive has writing on it's envelope, it reads "Rehearsal shots (Black)".
  - The Cradle will Rock 394, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marc Blitzstein, author (Black)".
  - The Cradle will Rock 412, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits (Wernli)".
  - Mr. Craig No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Created Equal No # A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage Models".
  - Created Equal No # B, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - The Crippled Girl 722, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Miss Baldwin, portrait (Steiner)".
  - Daly's Theatre 634, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Seating capacity (Nielsen)".
  - Dance 101, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audition (Waterbury)".
  - Dance 146, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Ballet audition Art of Theatre".
  - Dance 265, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Brooklyn Museum Sculpture Center; (Monoson)".
  - Dance 296, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Ballet, Campfire Girls (Black)".
  - Dance 558, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume pictures, Mermaids (Steiner).
  - Dance 772, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Miss Mehlman, portraits (Steiner)".
  - Dance of Death 22, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Dance 558A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives.
  - The Discriminating Princess 378, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama East Side House (Waterbury)".
  - Dr. Faustus 63, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cast portraits; Orson Welles".
  - Dr. Faustus 258, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots (Haber)".
  - Dr. Faustus 261, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Carol King, light technician Maxine Elliott's Theatre (Monoson)".
  - Dr. Faustus 273, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage Maxine Elliott's Theatre (Monoson)".
  - Dr. Faustus 290, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Devil stunts (Black)".
  - Dr. Faustus 292, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Drama critic's sign (Black)".
  - Dr. Faustus 343, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Brazilian actors attending performance Maxine Elliott's Theatre (Monoson)".
  - Dr. Faustus 357, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marionettes, operators with dolls (Arnold)".
  - Dr. Wespi 109, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "German unit (Waterbury)".
  - Doll's Holiday 356, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Public School #185 (Black)".
  - The Dragon Snee Zee 44, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marionette Biltmore Theatre".
  - The Dragon Snee Zee 49, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production".
  - The Dragon Snee Zee 88, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Edwards, Paul 887, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Edwards, Paul No # A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portrait (Rose)".
  - Edwards, Paul No # B, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Newspaper interview".
  - Einmal Menshe 249, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "German theater Yorkville Casino (Black)".
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 24, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children Adelphi Theatre".
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 96, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 113, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children audience Adelphi Theatre".
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 162, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caricatures".
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 169, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Majestic Theatre (Rappaport)".
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 201, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads " Foreign costumes (Horn)".
  - The Emperor's New Clothes 233, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Children's audience Heckscher Theatre (Waterbury)".
  - An Enemy of the People 888, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - An Enemy of the People 899, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Character shots (Waterbury)".
  - The Eternal Prodigal 243, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cast portraits; production shots; Ritz Theatre (Wernli)".
  - The Eternal Wanderers 117, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Madison Settlement House".
  - Evangeline 411, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Public School #124 (Arnold)".
  - Exodus 739, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dancers California, Los Angeles (Nielsen)".
  - Fair and Warmer 255, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Drama Grand Street Playhouse (Monoson)".
  - The Family Upstairs 390, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "The Family Upstairs".
  - Fantasy 1939 965, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dancers".
  - Fantasy 1939 967, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "(Nielsen)".
  - Farnsworth, William 312, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Farnsworth, William 344, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 97)
  - Federal Art Project 20, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Shots of Mr. Crampton".
  - Federal Art Project 141, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Sculptors at work".
  - Federal Art Project 153, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Art class YMHA".
  - Federal Art Project 180, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Museum exhibit; Museum of Modern Art (Rappaport)".
  - Federal Art Project 206, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Armory (Rappaport)".
  - Federal Art Project No # A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
  - Federal Art Project No # B, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
  - Federal Arts Projects 85, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Women's Exposition Grand Central Palace".
  - Federal Arts Projects 182, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads Exhibit 71st Armory (Waterbury)".
  - Federal Arts Projects 765, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Carnival Washington Square Park (Helkin, Rose, Steiner)".
  - Federal Arts Project No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "5 Arts Carnival".
  - Federal Music Project 119, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Brooklyn Symphony and New York Civic Orchestras Madison Square Garden (Waterbury)".
  - Federal Music Project 417, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "D. Plontnikoff, portrait".
  - Federal Music Project No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Mayor LaGuardia (Wernli)".
  - Federal Theatre Magazine 27, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Publicity stills".
  - Federal Theatre Magazine No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "George Ross, Alice Hughs (Wernli)".
  - Federal Theatre Project 18, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Set design".
  - Federal Theatre Project 28, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production chart".
  - Federal Theatre Project 55, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage workers".
  - Federal Theatre Project 58, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 98)